# Muhammad Taha



muhammadtahax@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/muhammad-taha-b83445148



https://github.com/AbsorbedInThought

#### Summary

I am an avid admirer of computer science and mathematics whose life's philosophy is "the will to find and consolidate the best in souls to ameliorate and innovate the way we thrive is the true success. It belongs to mankind as a whole."As I like to think that I have a fairly decent understanding of the mathematics and algorithms, the domain of app development, computer vision, data science and IoT interests me the most. Research and experimentation are the things that intrigue me and I am generally good at bringing ideas together to provide newer and more effective solutions.

#### **Experience**



#### Python/NodeJS Developer

Google Summer of Code

May 2020 - Present (9 months +)

Development of VisualCircuit Tool for JdeRobot in Python and NodeJS.

# Student

National University of Computer and Emerging Sciences

Aug 2017 - Present (3 years 6 months +)

# **Embedded Software Engineer**

Connect, Software Park I-9

Jun 2019 - Aug 2019 (3 months)

Development of a temperature, humidity and location tracking device on NodeMCU.

# Computer Vision Engineer

Uforia Logic

Feb 2020 - Apr 2020 (3 months)

From scratch development of a Semi-Automatic Background Removal Tool using OpenCV and Python.

#### Education



## National University of Computer and Emerging Sciences

Bachelor of Science - BS, Computer Science 2017 - 2021

# Punjab College of Science, Islamabad

F.Sc, Pre-Engineering 2015 - 2017



### SLS Montessori & High School, Islamabad

High School and Matriculation 2002 - 2015

### **Skills**

C++ • Python (Programming Language) • JavaScript • Assembly Language • Computer Vision • Image Processing • Data Science • Machine Learning • Internet of Things (IoT) • Flutter